# DHARMIT SHAH

+919925698090

 $GitHub \diamond Email \diamond LinkedIn \diamond Blog \diamond StackOverflow$ 

#### **SUMMARY**

Remote Software Engineer working in open source domain. Experienced in engineering (9 years), technical support (2.5 years), and user-facing roles (4 years); now focusing on getting into the depths of Go & Kubernetes. I have been working remotely since October 2015.

#### **SKILLS**

Primary Go, Linux, Kubernetes, Virtualization Secondary Bazel, Python, Ansible, Terraform, LaTeX

#### I AM PROUD OF

- End-to-end work on hook sidecar ConfigMap feature on an entirely new code base
- odo dev, concurrency (1, 2, 3) to improve odo logs performance, lead documentation effort. Created 12 videos for enablement of Technical Support, opened 18 bugs in the process, and received an award for the same
- Presented CentOS Container Pipeline Service in conferences and architected its v2 based on OpenShift 3

#### EXPERIENCE

### Senior Software Engineer, Red Hat

Oct 2015 - Present

• Developer on the KubeVirt team

Dec 2022 - Present

- End-to-end implementation and delivery for ConfigMap support in hook sidecar
- Use Operator framework to build and manage Kubernetes Operators
- Stack: Go, controller runtime, operator-sdk
- Developer and Team Lead for the odo project

Apr 2019 - Dec 2022

- Go CLI to deploy apps on k8s; extensively used concurrency primitives.
- Team Lead between Nov 2020 Dec 2021
- Lead the documentation effort: (website)
- Lead the effort to educate support team about the tooling.
- Stack: Go, spf13/cobra (CLI framework); goroutines, mutexes, sync/atomic (concurrency)
- Developer and Architect for CentOS Container Pipeline project

Mar 2016 - Apr 2019

- Service written in Python and deployed on OpenShift using Ansible
- Lead the architectural effort to move to OpenShift
- Stack: Python; Ansible & OpenShift (deployment); Jenkins Pipelines (build orchestration), beanstalkd (message queue); Prometheus & Grafana (monitoring)

# DevOps Engineer, Ishi Systems

Jul 2015 - Oct 2015

- Evaluate Apache Mesos on AWS using Terraform for application deployment
- Stack: Apache Mesos, Marathon, Chronos, AWS, Terraform, Ansible

### Software Engineer, Aubergine

Dec 2014 - Jul 2015

- Backend developer for the Cubii mobile app
- Design, develop and deploy the APIs
- Stack: Django Rest Framework, Celery, AWS

Associate Software Engineer, Red Hat

Jun 2014 - Nov 2014

• Worked on the ISV Certification team, and developed Dockerfile linter in Python

### Associate Technical Support Engineer, Red Hat

Apr 2012- Jun 2014

- Technical support cases for Linux, Virtualization and OpenStack platforms
- Front-line engineer, worked on call support

### Linux Administrator, Global SMS Networks

Dec 2011 - Mar 2012

• Setup firewall rules using iptables; admin for Web, FTP, Mail servers.

### IT Engineer, CMC Ltd.

Aug 2010 - Aug 2011

• Setup Oracle 10 rg2 on RHEL5.5; requirement gathering from the client.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Bachelor of Engineering, Information Technology

2006 - 2010

Sardar Patel University, Anand

### AWARDS & CERTIFICATIONS

# Red Hat Developer Impact Award

Dec 2019

Awarded for using the tool from a user's perspective, creating learning material for Technical Support team, and opening numerous bugs in the process

### Certified Kubernetes Administrator

Nov 2020 - Nov 2023

## Certified Kubernetes Application Developer

Nov 2020 - Nov 2023

# CONFERENCE TALKS

- DevConf.CZ 2018 at Brno, Czech Republic
- CentOS Dojo 2019 at Brussels, Belgium
- DevConf.CZ 2019 at Brno, Czech Republic

#### **COMMUNITY & MENTORING**

- Lead of Kubernetes and Docker meetup chapters in Ahmedabad
- Mentored undergraduate students in Linux & Python (references available on request)